elementor.com 2019-12-05

# Privacy Policy | Elementor.com

We recognize that privacy is essential. This Privacy Policy applies to all of the services, information, software, tools, features, and functionality, available or offered by us or our subsidiaries and affiliated companies. This policy covers how we collect and use personal data. 

In this policy, the term “personal data” shall be as defined in [Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation)](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/reg/2016/679/oj).

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us at admin@elementor.com.

## Your Consent

In plain English: **You don’t have to share data, but without sharing it, we cannot provide you with our services**.

Providing us with personal data is purely consensual. You are not obligated under any laws to provide us with any personal data, but without providing such personal data, we cannot provide you with the Services.

## Your Rights Under Applicable Laws

In plain English: **You are entitled to full legal protection, and we cannot take away your legal rights**.

##### Right of Access and Rectification

You have the right to know what personal data we collect about you and to ensure that such data is accurate and relevant for the purposes for which we collected it.

You can receive a copy of your personal data, and to rectify such personal data if it is not accurate, complete, or updated. 

However, we may first ask you to provide us with certain credentials to permit us to identify you before rectifying, deleting, or reviewing.

##### Right to Delete Personal Data or Restrict Processing

You have the right to delete your personal data or restrict its processing by ourselves and third parties.

We may postpone or deny your request if your personal data is in current use for the purposes for which it was collected or for other legitimate purposes such as compliance with legal obligations.

##### Right to Withdraw Consent

You have the right to withdraw your consent to the processing of your personal data. Exercising this right will not affect the lawfulness of processing your personal data based on your consent before its withdrawal.

##### Right of Data Portability

Where technically feasible, you have the right to ask to transfer your personal data in accordance with your right to data portability.

##### The Right to Lodge a Complaint

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with a data protection supervisory authority regarding the processing of your personal data.

#####  Your California Privacy Rights and Do Not Track Notices.

We do not convey your personal data to third parties for direct marketing purposes. 

However, if we did, then the California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal data to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  

To make such a request, please send an email to [admin@elementor.com](mailto:admin@elementor.com), and we will let you know that none of your personal data was shared. We are only required to respond to one request per customer each calendar year. 

We respond to “Do Not Track” signals.

## What Personal Data Do We Collect?

In plain English: **We may collect information you provide us when you use the services, software, and website**. 

We collect information in three different ways: when you use our website, when you use our services and when you use our software. 

##### When Using Our Website

In plain English: **We collect the information you provide us directly, and we collect information using technological means**.

We collect information you fill in registration forms, contact forms, forums, and comments, including your full name, address, contact information, approximate geolocation, and email address. We also collect payment information (for subscription purposes) and store a token for recurring billing if you purchased a subscription, which cannot be used to reidentify your credit card.

We also collect aggregated data from third parties, such as social media sites and other services which we use, and joint ventures we may establish.

We also collect the information that you submit to us via emails or other communication. 

We collect information relating to how you use our website, such as the pages you viewed, the links you clicked, the websites that referred you to us, your device type, screen resolution, operating system, and browser.

##### When Using Our Services

In plain English: **We collect information relating to how you used our service and contacted us.**

When you use our services, we may automatically collect information from your devices, including, without limitation, information and statistics about your online/offline status, your IP address, Internet service provider, type of browser, hosting environment, web server, your regional and language settings, and software and hardware attributes. 

Our systems may automatically record and store technical information regarding the method and nature of your use of the Services. 

In plain English: **We collect some information about how Elementor is being used if the Usage Data Tracking option is enabled.**

We collect the email of the website admin that uses our software, as well as some of the following, depending on your specific use: the IP address of said server, the license key, and the following information: Server software & version, MySQL version, PHP settings & version, WordPress version, WordPress debug mode, WordPress memory limit, WordPress max upload size, WordPress settings (permalink structure, multisite, language, theme, plugins), Site URL, number of custom templates saved to Library, number of posts using Elementor, and number of widgets used.

Even when the collection option inside the software is enabled, you can always choose to disable it by going to Dashboard > _Elementor > Settings_ and unchecking ‘Usage Data Tracking.’

## How Do We Process Personal Data?

In plain English: **We use personal data to provide you with software and services, to continually improve them, and to communicate with you.**

We use personal data to provide you with services and software.

We may conduct research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior based on personal data and other information we collect.

We may also disclose aggregated user statistics to third parties, including without limitation, to current and prospective business partners and other third-parties for other lawful purposes.

Information collected via the Software is used to help us understand how you use Elementor, and in what areas we could improve it. It shows us the areas that need more integrations and compatibility, and we analyze this to add new features to Elementor, as well as improve our documentation and tutorials.

We use third parties to send you targeted/interest-based ads, based on the personal data provided to us.

## Who Do We Share Personal Data With?

In plain English: **We share your personal data only under confidentiality obligations and only to provide you with software and services. We may disclose information to legal authorities.**

#####  International Transfer

Our servers may be hosted in various countries and jurisdictions that may be outside the country from which you access the Services and may be outside your country of residence.

We may transfer personal data across several countries. 

Some of the uses and disclosures mentioned in this Privacy Policy may involve the transfer of your personal data to various countries around the world that may have different levels of privacy protection than your country and may be transferred outside of the European Economic Area.

If there is a transfer of your personal data outside the EEA we will, in the absence of an EC Adequacy decision relevant to the destination country or the transfer, seek to rely on appropriate safeguards such as a valid Privacy Shield certification (in the case of a data transfer to a Privacy Shield certified US recipient):[ https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome)), or enter into appropriate EC approved standard contractual clauses (see[ http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/transfer/index_en.htm](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/transfer/index_en.htm)). 

##### Third-Parties

In plain English: **We use third-parties**.

As part of providing the Services our affiliates, agents, contractors, representatives, trusted business partners, and third-party service providers (including without limitation, the following entities) may have access to your personal data:

We use[ Google Ads](https://adwords.google.com/home/),[ Facebook Ads](https://www.facebook.com/business/products/ads),[ Twitter Ads](https://ads.twitter.com/),[ Microsoft Ads](https://bingads.microsoft.com/), [AdRoll](https://www.adrollgroup.com/privacy), and[ LinkedIn Ads](https://business.linkedin.com/marketing-solutions/ads) to reach our target audience with relevant ads. We use the data to track sales and other business goals, all the data is being masked, and the company can’t identify any action from a specific customer or user.

We use [CloudFlare](https://www.cloudflare.com/) to accelerate our web pages.

We use[ Facebook Messenger](https://www.messenger.com/) and[ Manychat](https://manychat.com/) to communicate with our users; each interaction is logged in Facebook Messenger.

We use[ MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/),[ SendGrid](https://sendgrid.com/),[ Jilt](https://jilt.com/), and[ HelpScout](https://www.helpscout.net/) to send promotional and support communications to our users. 

We use[ Google Analytics](https://analytics.google.com/analytics/web/) to analyze marketing goals and to integrate different data sources together.

We use [Green Invoice](https://www.greeninvoice.co.il/), [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/us/home), and [Stripe](https://stripe.com/) for our payment processing and accounting.

We require the foregoing parties to process such information in compliance with this Privacy Policy and subject to security and other appropriate confidentiality safeguards. 

If you used our services to contact a third-party, such as in our marketplace, then we will provide the information you filled out in the form to said third-party.

##### Legal Compliance

We may share information as required for the provision or maintenance of the Services. 

We may also share information in accordance with a written legal request by a valid legal authority. We will do our best to object to such request if we believe that it is baseless.

##### Merger or Reorganization

We may transfer data if we become involved in a reorganization, merger, consolidation, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of our assets, with any type of entity, whether public, private, foreign or local.

## Use Of Cookies, Trackers, and Remarketing Beacons

In plain English: **We may use cookies and trackers to provide you with the service.**

In order to collect the data described herein, we may use temporary cookies that remain on your browser for a limited period of time. 

We may also use persistent cookies that remain on your browser for the duration we provide the services. 

A cookie is a small piece of information which is sent to and stored on your browser. Cookies by themselves cannot be used to discover your identity. Cookies do not damage your browser.

Most browsers may allow you to block cookies, but you may not be able to use some features on the Services if you block them. 

You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie (this enables you to decide if you want to accept it or not).  

We may also use web beacons via the Services to collect information. Web beacons or “gifs,” are electronic images that may be used in our Services or in our emails. We use Web beacons to deliver cookies, count visits, and to tell if an email has been opened and acted upon.  
We also use third-party technologies, such as cookies and web beacons and various third-party providers (e.g., Google, Bing, Twitter, Facebook, etc.) to process and analyze your personal data, profile end-user activities and provide targeted ads, including without limitation tracking your use of the Services and third-party services and sites.

## Children

In plain English: **We don’t knowingly collect information about children**.

We will not knowingly contact or engage with children under the age of 16. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 16 has provided us with their personal data, please contact us, and we will act in accordance with the applicable law.

## How Can We Contact You?

In plain English: **We don’t spam; we will contact you with promotional offers.**

We may send you periodic notifications in relation to the Services or Software. We will also send you our newsletter, which you may opt-out of this service at any time by clicking the “Unsubscribe” button at the bottom of each promotional communication we send you.

Please note that different types of Services may have different newsletters managed by different lists. Therefore, unsubscribing from one list does not mean you unsubscribed from all lists.

## Complaints and Reports

In plain English: **We will deal with complaints and let you know the results of such investigation.**

We regularly review our compliance with this Privacy Policy.

Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or our treatment of personal data by contacting us as provided above. 

When we receive formal written complaints, we will contact you regarding your concerns. 

We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between the Company and an individual.

## Security Standards

In plain English: **We will do our best to be secure.**

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure, or destruction of personal data.

However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

We retain your personal data only for as long as reasonably necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or to comply with any applicable legal or ethical reporting or document retention requirements.

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

In plain English: **We may update this.**

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, and update you using the same method as when we update our terms of service.
